<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.triptico.minimum_profit</id>
  
  <name>Minimum Profit</name>
  <summary>A text editor for programmers</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>Unlicense</project_license>
  
  <description>
    <p>Minimum Profit (mp) is a text editor for programmers. Among its features are the following:</p>
    <ul>
    <li>Fully scriptable using a C-like scripting language.</li>
    <li>Unlimited undo levels.</li>
    <li>Complete Unicode support.</li>
    <li>Multiple files can be edited at the same time and blocks copied and pasted among them.</li>
    <li>Syntax highlighting for many popular languages / file formats: C, C++, Perl, Shell Scripts, Ruby, Php, Python, HTML...</li>
    <li>Creative use of tags: tags created by the external utility 'ctags' are used to move instantaneously to functions or variables inside your current source tree. Tags are visually highlighted (underlined), and symbol completion can be triggered to avoid typing your own function names over and over.</li>
    <li>Intelligent help system: pressing F1 over any word of a text being edited triggers the underlying system help (calling 'man' when editing C or Shell files, 'perldoc' with Perl, 'ri' on Ruby...).</li>
    <li>Understandable interface: drop-down menus, reasonable default key bindings.</li>
    <li>Configurable keys, menus and colors.</li>
    <li>Text templates can be easily defined / accessed.</li>
    <li>Multiplatform: Unix/Linux ANSI and Curses, Qt4/Qt5, GTK+, KDE4, MS Windows (both windowed and console).</li>
    <li>Automatic indentation, word wrapping, internal 'grep', learning / repeating functions.</li>
    <li>Spellchecking support (via the ispell package).</li>
    <li>Multilingual.</li>
    <li>Password-protected, encrypted text files (using the ARCFOUR algorithm).</li>
    <li>It helps you abandon vi, emacs and other six-legged freaks definitely.</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <releases>

    <release version="5.61" type="stable" date="2023-09-01">
      <description>

<p>New features:</p>
<ul>
<li>When the `tab' is hit while editing Makefiles, real tabs are always inserted, regardless of the configured tab to spaces conversion. This has been implemented by adding an optional function named pre_event(doc, key) inside a syntax highlight definition, that does the appropriate key conversion and it's called from mp_doc.pre_event() (contributed by aov).</li>
<li>Some enhancements to the hex viewer: character groups (control, printable, zeros, etc) are shown in different colors and a vertical, a left/right movable column is shown as a positioning aid, the `ctrl-g' keycode asks for an address offset to jump (Theo).</li>
<li>Input read from VCS commands is truncated to at most 2000 lines. This is to avoid waiting forever after commands that dump humungous amounts of data, e.g. from the `git log' of a very big project (contributed by Bix1994).</li>
<li>New clipboard configuration knobs: if the `mp.config.clipboard_file' variable is set to a usable file name, it's used as the interchange space instead of the system clipboard; if any of the `mp.config.clipboard_copy_prg' or `mp.config.clipboard_paste_prg' are set to program names, they are used as pipes to write to/read from the content of the clipboard (Claire).</li>
<li>A history of saved files (up to 100) is now stored inside the subdirectory `history' of CONFDIR as hard links (only supported on UNIX-like systems).</li>
</ul>
<p>Fixed bugs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed a bug when editing numbers in TUI forms (Tiny).</li>
</ul>
<p>Other changes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Replaced usage of strcpy() and sprintf() with other functions to placate some paternalistic compilers (Claire).</li>
</ul>

      </description>
      <artifacts>
        <artifact type="source">
          <location>https://triptico.com/download/mp-5.tar.gz</location>
        </artifact>
        <artifact type="binary" platform="x86_64-windows-msvc">
          <location>https://triptico.com/download/mp-5-portable-64.exe</location>
        </artifact>
        <artifact type="binary" platform="i386-windows-msvc">
          <location>https://triptico.com/download/mp-5-portable-32.exe</location>
        </artifact>
      </artifacts>
    </release>

  </releases>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">minimum_profit.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://triptico.com/software/mp-5-qt4.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://triptico.com/software/mp-5-curses.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://triptico.com/software/mp-5-ansi.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://triptico.com/software/mp-5-ansi-256.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://triptico.com/software/mp-5-gtk3.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://triptico.com/software/mp-5-win32.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
